Guide to the Betty Hawley Donnelly papers 1946-1970
Donnelly, Betty Hawley papers
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Betty Hawley Donnelly papers 1946-1970
5393
Donnelly, Betty Hawley
4 linear ft.
Photographs.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Correspondence and files of Betty Hawley Donnelly, vice president of the New York Federation of Labor and its successor, the New York State AFL-CIO.
4 cubic feet
A vice-president of the New York State AFL-CIO for fifty years and chairman of its committee on education. Donnelly also worked with the N.Y.C. Board of Education for forty years and was a member of the President's and Governor's Committees for the Physically Handicapped.
Consist chiefly of correspondence and reports concerning vocational education and health. Include correspondence (1939-1943) with the following: Ernest L. Stebbin (commissioner of health, City of New York), Lester W. Herzog (administrator, Federal Works Agency, Work Projects Administration), Frank Powers (Powers X-Ray Corporation), George F. Pigott (associate superintendent of schools), John E. Wade (superintendent of schools), and Hiram Jones (State Department of Education) regarding the vocational school x-ray survey, tuberculosis, and health programs in the New York vocational high schools; also reports on health instruction, physical examinations, physical fitness, tuberculosis, and the vocational schools chest x-ray survey; letters (1943) from members of the Assembly, State of New York (Albany) regarding the Vocational Schools Health Bill, Assembly PR 1627, Int. 1448; letters (1959-1960) regarding retail marketing in New York City; letters (1965) on Donnelly's retirement; condolence letters to Donnelly's son, John R. Hawley, upon her death (1970); requests for criticisms of curricula for courses in woodworking, carpentry, optical mechanics and retail distribution; and reports of the Committee on Education of the New York State Federation of Labor (1939, 1941, 1956). Also include a report of the New York City Board of Education's Advisory Board on Vocational Education to members of the Governor's Committee on Discrimination (1942); occupational survey of the food trades of the City of New York (1958); reports on job opportunities for electrical workers and automotive engineers; curricula outlines (1962-1963) for courses in food trades, beauty culture, automotive mechanics, sheet metal working, plumbing, machine shop and plastics; financial statements (1958, 1959), and routine letters (1929-1963) of the Petroleum Education Foundation chartered by the Regents of the University of the State of New York; interim report to study vocational education (1940); clippings; photographs; and printed and miscellaneous materials.
New York State AFL-CIO.; New York State Federation of Labor; United States. Federal Works Agency.; United States. Work Projects Administration.; Donnelly, Betty Hawley; Stebbin, Ernest L.
Automobiles -- Maintenance and repair -- Study and teaching -- United States.; Food service employees -- New York (N.Y.); Occupational surveys.; Occupational training -- New York (N.Y.); Occupational training -- New York (State); Vocational education planning -- New York (N.Y.); Labor leaders; Vocational teachers; Automobile industry. United States. Vocational guidance.; Beauty culture. Study and teaching. United States.; Electric industries. United States. Vocational guidance.; Food service. Study and teaching. United States.; Machine shops. United States. Vocational guidance.; Sheet-metal works. Study and teaching. United States.; Vocational students. Health and hygiene. New York (State).
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
- X-Ray Bill. Letters from Legislature, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Misc. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Materials on Tuberculosis X-Rays (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Misc. Pictures (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Misc. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Jobs. Retail Marketing Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sympathy Letters, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Petroleum Education Foundation, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Food-Maritime School (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Courses of Study. Committee of 9, 1934-1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1939-1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- An Occupational Opportunities Survey of the Food Trades, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Printing News, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Historical Background of the Advisory Board for Vocational and Extension Education, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Award Picture (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Betty Hawley Donnelly: Preamble and Resolutions Regarding Tribute (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Vocational Education and Guidance in New York City, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Certificate of Appreciation, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Certificates (Box 3, Folder 2)
- New York State Maritime College, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Certificate
- State of New York Executive Chamber, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 4)